Olubunmi Ruth Alao

Shttp://bumsyalao.me/ ■ bumsyalao@gmail.com Chumsyalao 🛅 /bumsyalao 📞 +971501507152

3+ years of experience in web application development, working mostly with JavaScript; React as frontend framework and NodeJS as backend solution. I understand business requirements, prioritise work based on highest business value and work with teams to solve problems.

Relevant Experience

Software Developer (contractor) at IBM

Dec 2018 - Present

Feb 2018 - Dec 2018

I worked on the TAMM Project here In Abu Dhabi. It is an impactful project aiming to revolutionise how citizens of Abu Dhabi interact with government services.

Built highly optimisied frontend visualisation of investment data using charts, graphs, highly interactive investment maps and business calculators for potential business investors.

Managed business processes with camunda business process modeler, while following agile software programming practices. Wrote Frontend and Backend tests.



Software Developer at Andela NG

Aug 2017 - Feb 2018

EFT Specialist at Interswitch NG

LoopBackJS

Remote & Freelancing

Production servers

Developer portal.

network traffic.

NodeJS

Jan 2016 - Aug 2017

React

IBM API Connect

I built Full stack applications using Micro-service for frontend and backend architecture while following agile software programming practices.

Wrote Front-end, Back-end and E2E test.

Contributed to Reaction commerce open source.

Contributed to Cards For Humanity, a fast-paced online version of the popular card game, Cards Against Humanity.



Full FEP Deployment, Upgrades, Maintenance & Support of core banking systems (Postilion, Postcard, Postilion Office).

I Worked remotely with engineering teams to build web applications

I worked on Stanbic Bank IBM APIC; Deployment of UAT, Test and

Set up network servers for the API Gateway DB, API manager and

Set up load balancers, to connect with the API cloud and manage

IBM Cloud

Networking

HSM (Hardware Security Module) Deployment.

Channel Enhancement & Certification (ATM, POS, WEB, and Mobile). Integration of external systems and networks. Examples: Integration to Processors/Switches (MasterCard, VISA, VERVE).

Installing, managing, upgrading and administering Microsoft SQL databases



Education

Covenant University

2010 - 2014

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

CGPA: 4.43/5

Final year project: A Computing Platform for Metabolic Network Visualization and Topological Analysis.

Selected Personal Projects

The-Consent-Game 2019 2017 Post-It

The consent game is built for The Consent Workshop, to teach young adults about consent.

Redux SCSS Javascript ES6 React

Post-it is a simple application that allows users create groups and post messages to group.

Javascript ES6 React SCSS PostgresSQL NodeJS Redux S post-it

2018 Ideabox 2017 **Flames**

Ideabox is a simple application that allows users to create a pool of ideas and promote collaboration.

NodeJS React Redux SCSS Mongoose Javascript ES6 ideabox [CSS] Javascript **♦** Flames

A game of love and prediction.

Selected Awards and Certifications

Front-End Web Developer **Microsoft Certified Professional** 2018 2016

Udacity Microsoft License 13392204

Python-codecademy **Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certification** 2017 2017 See certificate Codecademy

2016 **Postilion Basic Traning**

ACI worldwide